[Music]
hello and welcome to what's new in
Shopify connector especially B2B and
Order editing functionality I'm Andre
Pano and I will be doing demos for you
together with my colleagues josa and
onut
so I will start introd introducing the
changes we did to make Shopify connector
even better and then we will talk about
B2B from different perspective and then
also one of the uh Hot Topics is about
how to process order editing in both
products in parallel because this is
actually not trivial before now it's
much easier all
right uh let me start by demonst ating
you how Shopify connector actually
works all right let's go to the Shopify
shops I already created shop up front
because not not much magic here and now
I need to insert URL so for people who
were with using Shopify connector from
the moment it was launched they know
that it was dramatically easy in the
past because you can just go copy the
URL and insert it back uh it was not
working for some time since Shopify
switch to single Shopify admin URL but
now we actually update it and now it is
very easy so you can see that URL is
automatically updated so no need to
magically uh construct URL on the Fly
connector will do it for you then I will
activate connector
good and we are connected what else I
would like to show you right here let's
go to the list of locations and get the
list of locations we also noticed that
even if we provide extensibility which
allows you to have a multiple different
ways to calculate inventory one was very
popular it's a inventory minus
reservation so like a lot of customers
decided to build it themselves so we are
also adding this functionality out of
the box so for new Merchants they don't
need to build a PT and for existing ones
you can actually remove this
functionality and switch to the standard
behavior and it will should reduce the
cost of maintenance for you all right
now we have it configured very easily uh
before I will push data to Shopify I
also would like to go to the list of the
products and notice notice a
notification which actually helps you to
understand about the next step of course
if you're uh experienced user of Shopify
connector you already know which buttons
to press but for new people it's a good
reminder what to use and this is a
dynamic one so it can actually help you
to to decide about next step if you need
to push data to Shopify or imported from
Shopify then actions will be different
okay let me type in some uh some
filters because I want to export
everything in one
goal all right nice and easy quick look
at the Shopify list of products you can
see all products with images with
availability is here so simple as usual
what we added here as well I would like
to mention it uh before we move forward
further to B2B part I would like to also
show you the new uh setting which allows
people to decide if they want to send
shipment confirmation or not because
some companies are using digital goods
and they don't want to send extra
fulfillment details once the product is
uh shipped and fulfillment is registered
in business Central so now up to you
what you want to do next all right
another one uh makes sense to to notify
about the change that we are by default
importing uh refunds and returns so this
is a minor change which you also might
want to be aware now let's go and talk
about
B2B and and who is the best to tell
about Shopify B2B is of course experts
from Shopify and now we will see
presentation from Ben who will introduce
a B2B on Shopify shopify's Premier H
sale
solution thanks Andre as mentioned my
name is Ben rabi and I'm the senior
product lead for B2B on Shopify I'm here
to tell you a little bit more about our
suite of powerful B2B features that you
can now connect to business
Central to set the stage I want to give
you a quick overview of what B2B on
Shopify is B2B on Shopify is a suite of
powerful and flexible wholesale features
built right into the core of our
platform this means that Merchants can
leverage the full power of Shopify for
all sides of their business this also
means that B2B and Shopify is not a
separate platform it's not an app bolted
onto the side of Shopify and it's not
acquired software we built it right into
the
core now as the experts in Commerce
we've set out to revolutionize B2B in
Commerce just as we have for d2c with a
brand forward approach and hyperfocus on
ease of use and ability to grow to any
scale so what makes B2B and Shopify
different from other Solutions in the
market well first and perhaps most
importantly we offer a unified Commerce
experience Merchants can run their
entire business from a single platform
or even a single store with access to
all of shop of's most powerful features
that includes themes apis discounts flow
functions and more this means less
technical debt and higher return on
investment plus Merchants don't need to
hire developers to create and manage
their B2B store anyone on their team can
use our admin and feature set no coding
experience
required second with B2B and Shopify
Merchants have full control over the
buying experience this includes two
elements of customizations Merchants can
easily customize all of the wholesale
information available to their buyers
this means they can tailor product
availability price lits payment terms
payment and shipping methods and so much
more on a per customer basis all from
the
admin they can also personalize store
content and information based on the
type of customer they're selling to
whether it's B2B or d2c or the market
their customer is located
in and lastly B2B and Shopify offer
seamless integration to external systems
to allow our Merchants to operate with
maximum efficiency out of the box
Integrations and are close ties to
Leading Erp Partners like Microsoft
demonstrates our determination to make
it easy for merchants to run their
business from one Central platform and
with Microsoft business Central's
updated Integrations merchants can
easily send companies and cataloges data
from Shopify to business Central and
vice versa for better data accuracy and
Order
management since our initial launch of
B2B on Shopify we've released over four
dozen features just for wholesale the
list that you're seeing on your screen
is not an exhaustive list in fact no
other platform has moved faster to meet
the needs of B2B Merchants over the past
year we're committed to driving the
market forward by catering to the needs
of wholesale merchants of any size while
raising the bar for personalized B2B
buying and selfs serve experience
Shopify is all in on B2B
thanks all right uh thank you Ben for
showing with it's amazing let's see how
actually it works together with a
business Central and uh
today uh here with me we have onut who
will show how works on business Central
side and I will be the merchant or
Shopify admin who will be demonstrating
how it looks on Shopify
side thank you Andre um I want to start
first with a u a little uh Improvement a
slight change that we did on d2c
customer
synchronization um if you look at the
settings we have removed to export
customers to Shopify Boolean and instead
we aligned this uh with uh the item sy
so if you want to push a d2c customer
then you can always go to customers but
now you'll see um add customer button
just like what Andre showed um for items
um you can select one and then hit okay
and then Helen Ray is now uh
synchronized to Shopify let me
check okay I open the list of customers
on Shopify side and I can see the
customer yeah exactly as it used to be
but now is a more control so we can
decide exactly which customers we want
to export to Shopify as customers what
about companies okay let's look at
companies so um you can probably notice
this B2B company synchronization
settings on your shop cut if you have uh
a plan that you can use uh busines to
business in Shopify you'll see that uh
Tab and it looks very similar to
customer synchronization we wanted to
keep it in sync um but two uh main
settings here you can see the default
contact permission this uh allows you to
select the uh the default main contact
uh is created uh with what permissions
so it can be no permissions oring only
or location admin and we have also set a
setting for autoc creating catalog when
you uh create uh customers as companies
uh in Shopify let's see how that works
uh I go to related and companies and
just like d2c I can add a company and I
can select for example um School of Fine
Art hit
okay and now let's check withit Shopify
if that company is
created all
right let me refresh the list of
customers and now I can see customer
meant and if I will open the customer
card I can notice the difference now I
have additional fact box information
which shows that this customer is
actually linked to the company and you
can see that business Central added this
customer to School of Fine Art and also
this customer has some permissions to
specific locations all right let's go to
the list of
companies and I can see the company
created here as
well and this customer has a company has
a location and it has default customer
and if I will explore
the contacts so I can see that the Megan
is a main contact and I can also add
extra
ones all right I can also see the
catalog so we created catalog by default
what items this catalog has so I will go
to the list of products and I go to the
catalogs and I can see the catalog with
the same name as a customer so does it
mean that for each uh customer which we
export to to Shopify we will create a
separate catalog which we will need to
maintain uh no you don't have to do that
you can actually deselect also create
catalog and just create a catalog
yourself in Shopify and assign it to all
companies ahuh okay let me try it so I
will create a catalog and I will I would
like to include only specific
products because we exported both tables
and chairs in this case I will call it
B2B and I will save
it because we exported both t tables and
chairs I will repeat uh but for B2B
customers I would like only to to
include uh tables into the B2B catalog
chairs are for d2c customers only all
right include into the
catalog and now let's actually explore
how it
looks I will go to the online
store that's a default layout and I can
see a of products okay it's because I'm
a right now I am private customer who
have not authorized yet so I can
actually click on this aend desk and buy
it cloudon who surprisingly works very
close to Microsoft Office in
lumo we will use a special test uh
credit card
information no tips right
now and let's uh let's uh post it so you
remember that system asked for address
system asked for uh payment details and
it used the standard prices and it show
all catalog as well all right let's
continue shopping what if what if this
person is actually part of the
company Let's uh let's log in and let's
use uh
this account so for B2B or for modern
authorization engines Shopify doesn't
require user to know like login and
password so user needs to only specify
email and then they will get uh six
digit code to to to log in let me check
Inbox and I can see this six digigit
code which I will
copy and
insert
okay what will be the
difference surprisingly no difference
why so because this specific user and
this specific catalog are not yet
attached to the company so let me go to
the Shopify admin company and show you
how to replace uh catalog and how to add
extra user in the Shopify admin I will
go to the customers group then I will go
to the the companies and here I will
first of all add add a
customer so now we have a new one with
a with the email we'll save
it then we need to add a catalog we'll
go to locations and then we will change
the catalogs so I would like to remove
the uh standard
catalog this one and I would like to add
B2B save of course if we will create
customer without default catalog we can
do it we can do it differently all right
now I have a customer with uh attached
to the to the company and also B2B
catalog attach let's take a look at the
user experience so go to
home and back to catalog so first of all
you can see that list of product has
changed now have access to smaller
number of products but prices prices are
still the same what can we do with
prices yeah um let's switch back to
business Central and go to uh catalogs
this is a new action and now I can use
get catalogs uh select a shop and you
can see that I already got the um the
B2B catalog underr is created for School
of Fine Art company the other one that
we haven't got because we only look
through the um the cataloges for
available companies already synchronized
with business Central so now let me
maximize the screen and uh edit some
settings in order to sync prices first
I'll enable the sync prices then I'll
Define a um a discount group and then I
allow line discounts uh for this catalog
then I can use the um the sync prices
action to synchronize prices depending
on the settings I have set for each
catalog
now let's uh switch back to Shopify and
see the prices if they're synced all
right so I can definitely now see that
prices with discount so you can see that
original prices were reduced by some
percentage so now if I will place the
order I will add this table to the to
the card and then view the
card time to do check
out and this is how checkout window
looks for user who is linked to the
company so he is a representative of the
some company so you can see the user and
company name also the list of available
addresses company on Shopify site can
have multiple addresses uh and the user
might have access to one or many of
those it's on the Shopify side there are
permissions to to manage it then
payments payments are actually not
needed because we configured company to
not require credit card but actually to
to do payment outside of Shopify
checkout and before I will submit order
I can also enter the p number so this is
also a special field for B2B checkout
and this information will be transferred
to business Central so let me submit
this
order all right order is submitted and
now we will explore how it looks on uh
business Central site okay okay now
let's synchronize orders and see how
they look if I go to related and orders
use action syn orders from
Shopify click
okay okay uh now you can see I got two
orders um but the main difference is
although they were bought by the same
person Claudia Lawson one was actually
assigned to uh the person itself the
other one is assigned to the company so
one is a B2B uh the other one is a d2c
uh order so now uh because Claudia L
made a mistake and bought it herself
instead of buy the company I just want
to cancel the d2c order so I can open it
and then with a new action uh cancel
order I can cancel it uh notify the
customer the reason is customer
themselves uh refund and restock and
click okay okay the order has been
canceled successfully now I've handled
the B2B order if I open that one because
we uh Define a payment term and the uh
the customer will pay later I received
the payment uh in BC in that sense and
then now I can actually mark it as paid
and now the order has been Market paid
now let's switch back to Shopify and see
how that status looks all right what do
we see in the Shopify two orders and one
is Mark as canceled because we don't
want to ship it to private person uh
because this private person ask us to
cancel order and refund instead this
person placed an order on behalf the of
the company and you can see that now
this order is marked as
paid that's very good all right the
Fulfillment part will work as as usual
uh no surprises here uh now let's uh
let's talk about different aspect we saw
that how order was edited in business
Central which is new capability now
let's explore a different pers
perspective what if order is edited in
the Shopify for different reasons for
example exchanges or others and how it
will be handled by business Central so
what are we looking at so right now a
buyer placing an order with two items a
and desk and then mobile pedestal with a
new special sign to remove this is a for
us to better understand what is
happening yeah so it will be very easy
for us to see what's happening later all
right now I need to do check
out Lo on of every
customer uh the same address as
usual okay shipping method again
standard ones no
options test credit card and pay now but
right now customer is not that important
the most important part that this
customer wanted pull things and paid for
two things and later this customer
actually realized they did mistake uh
they didn't want to have a aens mobile
pedestal it doesn't fit the the the
apartment so they want to to remove it
so they they called Merchant and ask to
to change the order administrator will
go to the Shopify
admin find the
order and you can see that this order is
marked as paid uh now it's time to do
edit there are two options how to do
edits you can do refund and in this case
I will be removed and money will be
transferred back to the customer credit
card but not that simple so right now we
want to do a little bit more complicated
scenario which is more common in the in
the situation where Point of Sales is is
involved like when people want to
actually replace something so let's play
with this scenario I'm in the edit mode
I have two items and I would like to
remove one guess which
one and now I want to add another one
mhm very obvious one so I want to
replace table with chair that's how I
how how I want uh prices are different
let's not send any spam notifications
right now and update the document here
you can see that uh now because of the
price difference between uh products we
still need to do some refund it's a
small amount so we will do this 280 so
let's do refund as a separate
transaction
and this is exactly what we going
to to refund
28 240 and 80 80 Crown let's not do any
sense do you want to specify any reasons
not
today refund okay so what I did I
removed one item added another and I
actually refunded the Delta what will
happen in business Central
Joshua yeah welcome thank you so yeah
let's see uh so as you saw Andre just
created a very uh complicated order and
let's see how we manage things after
some edits so when we are in the Shopify
orders and we decide to synchronize our
orders you'll see this is the order that
Android just created for
us and if we open it we will see some
things
so it will just have the items that was
originally here and the item
to but it will also have two different
refunds so this is because Shopify
tracks edits as uh refunds but only the
one that is that has an actual amount is
the one that we want to track or to
create a credit memo
from so let's go ahead and well first
let's map this to an
item
and
yeah so the checks are that whenever we
want to create credit memos before we
just could create any uh credit memo
from every refund and now we uh make
sure that we have an actual amount and
we can create link the appropriate
credit memo that matches the refund that
we created on Shopify site ahuh amazing
so I actually added stuff removed stuff
and in the order which you imported into
the business Central we only have the
items which has to be shipped and for
and we also created credit memo only for
for Delta amount which will need to
return back to the customer that's good
I saw that you actually created orders
and credit memos already but now uh
because you imported them into the
business Central but what if I will
continue editing order so like I'm again
in the same order which was already
slightly edited I will continue my uh my
exercises here and I will remove another
item for example I will remove this time
a
desk all right what will you say for
this challenge okay so it is problematic
now because now the s sell order is a
document in business Central already so
and we do not know the processes that
each company may have so we cannot
assume a lot but let's see let's just
try to synchronize orders and see what
happens okay so when it tries to it will
now detect that it has some errors so
this will show whenever uh an order has
already been processed but now an
addition is received on line S on
something that impacts the amount so to
resolve this that is uh up to the
processes of the companies but we
provide now
two uh main actions in order to do this
one is synchronized order from Shopify
and the other one is onlink process
documents in this case the edit that
Android made was removing this aens desk
so this happened after this order was
paid so we probably want to have a
credit memo for this also no so but we
already had a sales order that had this
Athens dis okay okay let's say for the
sake of it that this time we will cancel
the sales order create a new one and
yeah we will deal with this as a new
process okay so we delete the
order and now this is like this now but
we can also
unlink okay so this is basically saying
forget what I had before and I want to
reprocess this
again and it will be processed as new
and it will just have the order line
that we expect to have and it will have
the
refunds that we expect also to
have or well in this case Android
removed one so that's why here you say
you see that there is just one with zero
but it he didn't trigger the refund I
believe so yeah that's why we cannot
create a credit M for this one but for
this one you can so we're basically
providing some building blocks so that
you can uh yeah get yourself out of
these complex situations where there are
edits on one side and then you process
the order and so on so and now you can
have things in sync and correct them as
you need with these two little actions
yeah I understand the challenge is is
big one because Shopify doesn't have
much information about the Warehouse
handling of the created order so it
might be on different stage even be
already sh uh in the car so we cannot
automatically modify the documents but
we can give users notification that
something is not exactly right and give
tools to address the situation and then
it might be uh Recreation of sales
document or it might be asking for house
employee to stop the processing and do
some uh adjustment on on a later stage
but also uh in cases where it's easy to
deal with for example if document was
not imported at all we just
magically prepare document with only
important information and then user
should not do any extra extra actions I
think this is a reasonable approach this
slide actually summarize summarize what
Shopify allow us to do so like for
orders without payments we can do edits
for orders which are already paid you
can do either Ed it and refund
separately or actually refund all
together and uh in business Central be
process it one way or another like
either we will edit the imported
document or we
will uh create credit memo which also
can be created
automatically and if uh document in
business Central like order or credit
memo was already created then we will
show the the warning and notification
all right so thank you for watching and
thank you for sharing feedback and for
using the Shopify connector uh we hope
that you will enjoy the new
functionality and we will have like even
more customers uh benefiting from from
this
integration you can always uh reach out
to Microsoft via different channels and
share your questions or feedback or
product
suggestions uh looking forward to
hearing from you thank
you